KITSUDAR SOMCHANA

UX/UI DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

720-232-7579 kitsudar@gmail.com I am designer with a strong blend of creativity and front-end web development to create dynamic user experiences. I am a motivated self-starter who has the ability to transform ideas into user friendly, captivating designs and deliver results in a fast-paced environment.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, jQuery/JavaScript, Bootstrap, Photoshop CC, Illustrator CC, Indesign CC, After Effects CC, User Experience/User Interface, Responsive Web Design, Git/Github, Logo/Branding/Styleguide

EXPERIENCE

Alcohol Monitoring Systems, Littleton, CO Present - 2015 UX/UI Designer

Responsible for the creation of a stellar user experience for the company's software applications for desktop and mobile platforms.

- Work in a kanban agile environment and understand product development life cycle.
- Create wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps as needed to effectively communicate interaction and design ideas.
- Implement bootstrap framework to the old .NET web pages so it's responsive and mobile friendly.
- Work on the design and development of the mobile applications, native IOS apps and native container app.
- Create hi fidel prototypes using HTML, css and jquery that is development ready.
- Work with developers, QAs, business analyst and product managers to make sure the products meet the business requirements and software requirements.
- Work with overseas developers as a UI resource and provide front-end trouble shooting.
- Maintain and promote digital style guide so the developers and QA can use as a resource for best practices and standards.
- Create graphical assets as needed to assist other business segments.

RTD, Denver, CO 2015 - 2013 Graphic/Web Designer

As a designer, I am responsible for the comprehension of the brand and bringing it to life in form of best in-class customer experiences. I worked on award-winning creative campaigns, as well as base level system projects.

- Worked on converting the RTD main site to be responsive by the combination of fluid images, fluid grids, and media queries. Used digital style guide with similar framework as Bootstrap to convert web pages to be responsive.
- Redesigned the base system information platforms for RTD users; including bus stop signs, schedules and shutter boards. Focused on the user experience through the redesign process.

Hogan Lovells, Denver, CO 2012 - 2011 Contract designer

Responsible for the design of graphic applications such as collateral material, custom proposal graphics, ads, info sheets, custom invitations, signage, firm publications, and electronic invites and communications.

MoneyGram, Lakewood, CO

2011 - 2009

Contract Designer

I supported the marketing department by creating media such as direct mail, advertisements, brochures, presentations, signage, promotional materials and collaterals as needed. Acted as a liaison between the Denver and Dallas offices during relocation transition.

Munchkin, Inc. North Hills, CA

Senior Graphic Designer

2009 – 2006 As a senior design

As a senior designer, I lead a team of 3 in house designers as well as designers in our Hong Kong office to help produce print and packaging for baby and pet products. Projects included annual sales catalog, packaging designs, tradeshow materials and sales presentations.

Patina Group, Los Angeles, CA 2006 - 2005 Graphic Designer

I worked alongside the marketing team to help maintain Patina Group's unique upscale dining experience at landmark locations in Los Angeles and New York. Created various materials for Restaurant Associates + Patina Group such as menus, promotional mailers, sales sheets and catalogs. Negotiated and maintained printing cost, reviewed and attend the final press-checks.

EDUCATION

University of Denver

Graduate Certificate, Advanced Study in Web Design and Development, 2014 - 2015 California State University-Long Beach

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA), Graphic Design, 2000 - 2004

References available upon request.